There is a brother there who has a problem with his marriage - you have a marriage problem.
You and your wife are there. Please, come out.
Don't be shy.
The couple whom the prophecy concerns comes out to confirm the words of the man of God.
You will not leave this wife. She needs deliverance.
She has a spiritual husband. Okay?
Amen.
And as for you, you know this is the problem you have been facing.
Disappointment has been your problem.
You always meet these people - spiritual husband.
This is not your first time.
You have experienced it in the past.
Yes, Man of God.
Disappointment is not from this woman alone.
You had disappointments in the past.
Amen.
Even this one has a very strong spiritual husband.
Which one is "Amen"?
Whatever the man of God is saying is very true.
I am the man of whom the man of God said that I have a problem with the marriage.
I am a pastor and the speaker of the council.
My wife is here and she is having extramarital affairs.
It is disturbing my ministry.
Look! Did you listen to what I'm saying?
Yes, sir.
When somebody has a spiritual husband, she is not your wife; she is somebody's wife.
Okay?
Yes, I understand.
It means, the two of you married this woman.
So, okay?
Help us, Man of God.
You said you are a pastor.
Yes, Prophet.
Spiritual husband means, someone is in the spirit and you are in the physical
and the two of you married her.
Deliver us, Man of God.
How can you now claim that she is your wife?
This woman needs to be delivered. You will not leave this woman. Okay?
Amen.
She is a good woman.
Please, help us, Man of God.
This is what you are saying now -
you say, somebody is on the moon, somebody is on the sun, somebody is in the south.
Okay! You will be delivered. She is your wife.
Madam, how are you?
All her character and attitude is as a result of the spiritual husband. Okay?
Yes, Prophet.
If you don't deliver her and leave this woman, you will meet another one
that has two husbands in the spirit.
Thank you, Prophet.
So, don't worry. I want to be a part of your family. Okay?
Amen.
Thank you. It's alright.
Man of God, please, deliver me.
Don't worry.
At The SCOAN, Prophet T.B. Joshua ministers spirit-filled prayers to the people, in Jesus' name.
And whatever that is planted in their lives that is not of God is commanded out, in Jesus' name.
Among them is the couple who received the word of prophecy during the service.
He prays for them and delivers them, in Jesus' name.
Manifestation Of Evil Spirits
Who are you in her?
What have you done to her marriage?
No marriage there.
This is my wife. The marriage is not okay.
The man of God prophesied that there is a man here together with his wife
who has challenges in the marriage.
I confirm that is true.
The man of God also said that my wife has a spiritual husband.
This is the manifestation of what the man of God has said.
Thank God for the deliverance.
No marriage here.
Why did you say, "No marriage"?
Why?
Do you see a marriage here?
What did you do to the marriage?
No marriage; it is finished.
It is finished.
How did you do it?
I destroyed the marriage.
How? What did you push her to do against this marriage?
Speak out!
Look at me alone.
Who are you to her?
I am the husband.
How did you enter her?
When she was young.
Manifestation Of Evil Spirits
With just a touch from Prophet T.B. Joshua, the lady and her husband
fall under the influence of the Holy Spirit and they are delivered, in Jesus' name.
Glory be to God!
Thank You, Jesus! My wife is delivered, my marriage is delivered.
We thank God.
Thank You, Jesus!
CHANGING LIVES
So viewers, when God speaks, changes are beginning.
Let's get ready to hear from Pastor Mokoena and his wife.
Good Morning to you, program directors.
My name is Pastor Mokoena.
Usually in my country, they call me Pastor Tony.
The woman sitting beside me is my beautiful wife. This is Lerato Mokoena.
It has never really been easy in our marriage.
We have been married for 15 years now.
In these 15 years of our marriage, we only enjoyed the marriage for two years.
It has really been tough.
Now you can understand - being 15 years in a marriage and enjoying it only for two years.
The rest of 13 years - it has been a pain. Pain after pain.
I would go to church with a broken heart.
But I would keep on persuading, preaching to the people of God.
And really, it was not an easy journey for both of us
because firstly, when I met her, there was that love between both of us.
We cannot tell what happened during our stay together.
Sometimes, I would be preaching in church and she'd just decide to take her handbag and leave the church.
That thing would be disturbing the entire congregation.
But people are used to things.
Actually, nobody in church could understand what was happening with my wife.
Sometimes, she couldn't even clean in the house, she would just leave the house dirty,
the dishes would be filling the ... I had to do all this housework -
I had to clean, I had to wash the dishes,
sometimes I even had to wash the clothes.
You mean her clothes?
Yes, even the children's.
Sometimes, when the children were going to school, I had to prepare them to go to school.
Sometimes, this young man, my elder son - he is 12 now -
when he was still a baby and crying all evening, my wife would just neglect him.
I had to take care of the son and try to make him sleep.
It has affected me mentally, it has affected the church -
some people would just come and leave,
saying that there is no union between the man of God and his wife.
You mean, was it that evident, that people could notice that your wife was not with you in the ministry?
Yes, madam. People would see it.
As I am saying to you, when I approached the pulpit to preach, she would just take her handbag and leave.
Right in the church?
Right in the church.
In the presence of the whole congregation?
Yes.
I would be so embarassed.
But because people came to church, there was a time, whereby I said,
"It is not about me but it is about the people of God who came to listen to what God is saying".
But the Lord really sustained us in the very same problem that we have faced in our marriage.
Sometimes, she could not even sleep with me.
She would just get off the bed and go to sleep on the couch.
It was a struggle.
Sometimes, people didn't understand. - "Why are you behaving in a manner that is not godly?"
They are not staying in your house; they don't know what is happening in your house.
And all they would do is just gossip and such.
Yes, gossiping and such - they would be pulling my name into the mud.
The church would be pulled into the mud. It was not an easy journey.
Some pastors - I would be there preaching on their pulpits.
They would see. Sometimes, people would talk to them, "There's no peace in that man's house".
I think at this point I would like to ask you a question, Pastor.
Going by the prophecy of the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, when he gave you that prophecy
along with your wife, saying that your wife was being tormented by a spiritual husband -
tell us, what was life like - apart from the physical things you could see?
Did you experience any kind of attacks? With those habits she had - what was life like,
being tormented by this spiritual husband that possessed your wife?
Yes, this spiritual husband has tormented me so much.
In one of the years, the community called me to come and be part of the politics.
I just went there as a minister of the Gospel trying to assist the governor at that time
in the sphere of ministers' fraternal.
It happened, when her term finished, people wanted me to lead the community.
I accepted the call; I became a governor in the world.
It has never been easy in politics. I was hated all over.
But God saw me through until my term was over.
But before the term was over, there had been so many unrests in my community.
They wanted to burn my house, to burn the church
For what good reasons? Nobody can tell.
But by the mercy of the Lord, when my term was finished, I wanted to quit politics.
But the premier of my province said, "No, there is no need for you to quit.
We need people like you, we need ministers of God to assist us".
I accepted the call, I became the speaker of the council.
But still being a speaker, I was no longer handling a ward, whereby I interacted with people monthly,
except when we were going to do a public participation, where I would be assisting the ward councillors.
But this spiritual husband was still tormenting me.
People still wanted to... When you went on Facebook, they would be saying bad things about me.
They would be saying, "I must be removed as a speaker" - all those things.
But you can see that there was an evil force that has been pushing people to do such things to me.
At that time did you actually know that it was something spiritual
or you just thought that it was one of those things?
As I have been following Emmanuel TV, it came to my senses that there was a demon behind this.
I didn't even know that I would get used to such a situation.
Because it was hard on the street, in politics, hard in the house, church, meeting attacks -
I never had peace.
I think at this point I would like to ask madam:
Let's go back to the prophecy the man of God gave to you
during the service when he said that you had a spiritual husband.
I think the viewers would like to know, what it was like -
to be married not to a physical husband but a spiritual husband.
Just to confirm what your husband has been saying so far.
My name is Lerato Mokoena. I come from South Africa.
Coming to your question, I didn't have an idea that it could be that.
I knew we had a problem and, as he said, we both believed that there was a spirit behind it
but not specifically knowing what kind of spirit it was.
And when the man of God gave us the prophecy that this is a spiritual husband,
I could relate, I could understand that this is indeed what has been troubling us all our life.
Because I would always hear my husband complaining to me, "You are so loud,
you are so violent and you fight about even the smallest things".
His main complaint was that I was not submissive.
He would always utter words like, "There are two men in the house".
Yes, that's what I usually said.
I was saying, "You don't listen to me, you don't respect me, it's like we are two men in this house".
She behaved like a man?
She behaved like a man.
I would realise that he was not dealing with a woman.
He then became so abusive,
trying to enforce the respect and submission that he was requiring from me.
And I would still pray, I would still do what was expected of me like feeding my spirit
and I would go to church on sundays but during the week - no mid-week activities.
Can we say that at that time you were just doing those things
but your heart was not really focused on them?
At that time I thought everything was fine; I thought I was doing the right thing;
I thought all was still fine. But only to find out that I was just fooling myself.
Let me say, you had two faces then.
Maybe during this time you might be laughing but you were not actually laughing,
or going to the church, helping your husband in the ministerial affairs
and you were not actually doing that on the outside.
You had two natures which people did not really understand.
Yes, because I would feel that he did not want me there, he did not need my help.
Hence, I would stay back and not be involved in most of the activities that were happening in church.
Because in a way, the reflection I would have of him was that he didn't want me to be involved.
That was what came into my head.
From what you have just explained now, I think the viewers will understand
that this was basically two natures of madam and two faces because as she said,
people did not really see the deeper side of her, that there was something behind this behavior of hers.
I mean when she laughed, she was not actually laughing because there was a demonic influence somewhere.
A demonic force.
Because sometimes, when I was preaching, she would be holding her phone, playing with it.
Lerato, can I just chip this in?
Because at that time, when you were having this crisis in your marriage,
was it like a constant war in your heart - maybe one desires to do the right thing,
one desires to be submissive, then another voice would tell you, "No!"
and bring his wrongs to you - and that would make you react negatively?
So I think that is what Folake means by saying that you had like two faces.
Yes. At times I would just say, "From now on, going forward, I am just going to do what he wants.
I am just going to make sure that everything he asks from me, I will do it and I won't wait until he complains".
Especially concerning the issues that he was talking about - that I was not washing his clothes.
I would have a problem, especially with the underclothes. He would complain.
Even if I could do other things, I would not do them.
But at some point I would tell myself, "I am just going to do everything right,
I am just going to do the laundry, I am just going to do..."
But only to find out, it didn't happen. I didn't do it, and when he came home,
sometimes I would be apologising, sometimes I would be just quiet,
saying in my heart, "Why don't you do it yourself?"
That's what Prophet T.B. Joshua says that we don't have enough physical strength to fight satan.
Once the force behind it is satanic, demonic, physically we cannot fight this battle.
It's just by the strengh of God.
It's very true.
CHANGING LIVES
It has never really been easy in our marriage.
We have been married for 15 years now.
In these 15 years of our marriage, we have only enjoyed the marriage for two years.
It has really been tough.
Now you can understand - being 15 years in a marriage, enjoying only for two years.
I understand.
Sometimes, she would just leave me alone in the house and visit another town
so that she could not come to church on Sunday,
so that she could go to another church rather than coming to my ministry.
Sometimes, being a minister of the Gospel, you can assist people to grow.
Some would come to church without knowing how to play the keyboard, instruments -
you would find people to train them. Once they know - they think they know - they leave.
There were times when in my ministry, we didn't have a keyboardist.
My elder son would be helping me playing the CD, when I preached.
He would just put the CD and play it, and I would preach.
Do you know what was happening? To show that it was an evil force that was pushing my wife,
she would take the very same person who was trying to assist me in the ministry,
together with his younger brother, to another place
so that I would stay there alone and struggle with the work of God.
So can you just let us know what finally happened that she agreed to come with you to The SCOAN?
As I was saying, I had tried to persuade her to come, but she even said to me,
"I am not going to go to The SCOAN".
She told you plainly.
"I am not going to go to The SCOAN." But I kept on praying.
I had prayed a lot for us to come here. Sometimes, I would be fasting for 21 days,
praying for God's intervention because I knew, once we came here, solution would come.
Actually, we were at the edge of divorce.
But I just said, "Let me come to The SCOAN so that we can get God's opinion".
By the mercy of the Lord she ended up agreeing to come with me to The SCOAN.
And actually, a few days before we came, she was driving home after work
and she had an accident. And I told her, "No, don't worry about that".
We know, every time when we plan to go, all the spirits will be trying to fight, doing whatever.
She had an accident, her car got scratched, the person they hit - the mirror just broke and fell down.
She came home. And we were still struggling to find her passport.
So many things were just...
The man of God usually says, when you are getting close to your breakthrough,
then the battle becomes hotter.
So I think, from what you just said - that means that her deliverance started from home.
Yes.
If not, there was no way, she would have followed you to The SCOAN.
Sometimes, it even happens in real life, I mean in the world there,
you would just see some hardened, very tough criminal just wake up in the morning
and say, "Can you take me to Jesus".
What happened? You know, that nothing starts from outside the home - it must start from home.
Charity begins at home. That is why she agreed first at home.
And that was why she decided to come to The SCOAN.
Lerato, I think I would like to ask you one more question before we wrap up.
At the time the man of God touched you, when you finally came here,
and after the prophecy, you were opportuned to be at the prayer line.
When the man of God gave you that touch, tell us - what did you experience at that time?
Immediately the man of God laid his hand on me, I felt so angry.
I don't know why.
When I was standing in the queue, I was anxious, hoping that this was my time to receive a touch.
But the moment he laid his hand on me, it was like he was provoking,
it was like he pushed a wrong button.
I felt like I didn't know what was wrong with me now
and what I can remember is that I felt anger.
Exactly! Because at that time - we could see from the clip - you were kicking.
She even kicked me!
You gave your husband a karate kick.
Karate kick? Me?
You were so unconcious of everything around you. You kicked!
And even the men around could not hold you!
How many men?
Can we say, like two or three men?
They were many there!
You were kicking.
I was very surprised because the very same leg that she kicked me with -
she had an ankle problem. So I was surprised. Today the lady is now able to walk.
You should ask yourself, "How come a leg with a problem was able to kick?"
To show you that there was another leg!
That was that spiritual husband's leg.
That's why when the man of God gave the prophecy, he said,
"Man, this woman, she has two men - you and another man in the spirit".
We saw that evil man manifest that day.
Yes. When I got the kick, I said, "No, that man is kicking me now".
Yes, that's true.
Going by that experience you had, you said, it just got you angry.
It shows that you sensed that touch from Heaven; that fire was upon you.
I believe so.
And it was that fire of the Holy Spirit you received through the touch of the man of God,
Prophet T.B. Joshua, that made you so unconsious of everything
because it was a touch from the Holy Spirit.
It was the power of God that descended on you and made that demon to manifest.
And you became unconsious of your enviroment because you were influenced by the Holy Spirit.
So it was a great experience and we know that it was that experience
that has brought this beautiful smile on your face.
I really thank God for that moment. I can't explain how I feel now,
after that life changing touch - I will call it my "miracle touch".
What do you want to tell viewers about that touch?
Viewers, everyone needs that touch. Because even after that, I still feel that hammer on my head.
And when I went to bed to sleep, it was like I was a baby. I slept peacefully.
And I enjoyed my sleep. Even in the morning when I woke up, I felt so light and I thank God for that.
I don't have words to explain how my life is now.
Even the morning after my deliverance, I woke up with the joy of the Lord overflowing in my spirit.
The first thing I did that morning was just to call my husband to find out how he was.
I felt really like I missed him already.
I felt differently from all other days about how I feel about him.
And I thank God for that.
And how did you feel when you received that call - first of its kind in 15 years of marriage?
It was an overwhelmimg moment - something that I've been longing for for years.
I had always been complaining to her that if I didn't check on her, she didn't check on me.
It takes two to tango.
I felt so very blessed when she called me that morning.
One thing that she forgot to mention - immediately after that touch from Heaven,
the very same ankle that was having a pain - that pain was gone.
She has been trying to check - the pain was no longer there.
Thank You, Jesus.
So it was not just deliverance from that spiritual husband.
Everything about her health was restored.
Yes, it was indeed. As we were staying there, we were going up the stairs.
Every time I would climb stairs - one stair with both feet, first one and second one.
The next one - the first one and the second one.
Every time I had to make sure that I started with the right one and pulled the aching one.
But now I am able to climb up and down the stairs without pain.
Even at night, I would be twisting my ankle just to check if the pain is there
but to the glory of the Lord, no pains until now.
And your children - have you heard from them?
Yes, we heard from them.
Even today we were speaking to them - they are all well.
I believe, when we get back home, we will be a joyous family together, we will be a happy family
to the glory of the Lord, we will do God's work together, holding hands and closing every rank
that was there before the deliverance and do God's work.
Folake, would you want to give us the question from our viewers?
Pastor Abraham and the wife, what you have shared with us so far has been very educative
and I believe our viewers have really enjoyed it - the experience you have shared so far.
We would like to ask you many questions, if you don't mind but time will not permit us.
We just want to take one of the many questions that have come in to our program today.
And it's from Pastor Eric from the USA and he is asking about the changes
you have both seen in your marriage after the deliverance.
Thank you very much for such a beautiful question.
After the deliverance, we are now eating together.
She can feed me, I can feed her which was the thing that was no longer happening.
We even study and read the Word of God together. We feel very blessed with that.
We will now be planning the future together.
It's nice. We are walking around here holding hands
which was a thing that was no longer happening in our marriage.
We thank God. Indeed, it's a new beginning of our marriage.
I'm drunk in love. I'm really happy.
One statement he said to me was, "I wish we can get married now.
We will do everything afresh now".
I think that this is really something that will highlight this whole thing,
this whole new beginning that we are experiencing now.
I will never stop thanking God for this revival
because now a new thing has been born and I will never stop telling my husband
how much he means to me and I will be that woman that he expects me to be,
that woman that is abiding by the standards of the Word of God
and do exactly what is expected of me as a woman, especially one who is married to a man of God
who needs my support, my prayers, who needs me beside him in everything he is doing.
So I have really made a decision that I will stick, I will be there -
as long as God is by my side, I can do great exploits.
Yes, we know that as Mrs Mokoena has made that decision,
God will definitely give you the energy for the distance.
We really thank God for this.
Thank you.
On that note, we want to really thank you for coming and sharing this experience with our viewers.
We know they have also been blessed, touched
and their lives will never be the same by this your experience. Thank you.
We also thank you for the invitation.
Viewers, we have heard it all.
A relationship does not involve two perfect people.
I mean such perfect people don't exist on this planet.
You're very right, Folake. Because the origin of any relationship is God,
and if God does not release us and we quit a relationship
or reject anyone on account of their weakness,
we will quit the next relationship in the same manner and even the next one after it.
I think you're right, Ann. Relationship is all about beneficial cooperation.
Human relationship is very important, especially in an institution such as marriage.
Exactly.
But I'm just surprised of what is happening all over the world today -
distrust, infidelity have been the order of the day in most marriages.
Exactly, Folake.
And I think we need to know God's time in this matter.
If you look at Malachi 2:16, God declared, "For I hate divorce". And that is God speaking.
Exactly.
So what does this mean to couples all over the world?
It means that as a child of God, divorce is never the will of God for your marriage.
And when a situation like this arises, what do we need to do?
We need to dig deep and fight it through.
There are powers in this world that will naturally want us to be bowed down in bondage,
and if we fail to realise this, we will continue to fight the wrong battle,
we will continue to disengage ourselves from the wrong relationships,
we will continue to do the wrong things and affect our homes, our marriages.
So there are powers that want us to be bowed down in bondage - we must begin to realise this.
I personally have never seen where hatred would overcome love.
Never.
Love of God overcomes.
If you have the love of God in your heart, you will overcome,
just as Pastor Mokoena and his wife did.
So viewers, show the love of God in your relationship and you will overcome the challenges that you face.
On this note, we will draw the curtain on today's program.
From me, Anne - remain blessed.
And from me, Folake - stay in faith.
Pastor & Mrs Abraham Mokoena
BITTER JOURNEY BECOMES SWEET
I love you.
Thank you very much.
Pastor & Mrs Abraham Mokoena
BITTER JOURNEY BECOMES SWEET
Thanks for watching Changing Lives -
Send Us An E-Mail: info@scoan.org
Call Us On +234(0)8080800044, +234(0)8088096917,
Share Your Testimony: +234(0)7086977000, +234(0)8120271044.
Changing Lives
BITTER JOURNEY BECOMES SWEET
A production of SCOAN
In association with Emmanuel TV
TT: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 12/07/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 31/07/2018